I have good news VMware
Workstation is
free I have been a VMware Workstation
Pro customer for more than six years and
I've had to pay you know $200 to $300
every time I did it but now now that
broadcom got a hold of
VMware VMware
Workstation and workstation Pro which is
confusing
because the pro version for pros is not
free all let me say this again
workstation Pro for personal use is
free workstation Pro for professional
use still costs money but if you're like
me I don't use it for professional use I
use it because I'm at home I'm in my
home lab and I'm testing things and I'm
looking at how they work and
everything and for the beginner boost
which if you don't know about the
beginner boost there's been people have
in the past said well we're going to use
we're going to use uh virtual box which
by the way don't use Virtual bikes if if
if virtual box wasn't dead before when
they said they weren't going to support
arm and then they were forced to do it
anyway and all the bugs I mean serious
serious major bugs in in Virtual buck
and being owned by Oracle if all of
those reasons weren't enough for you to
run screaming from virtual box because
it was free
the last reason is now gone VMware
Workstation Pro the best virtualization
product on the market hands down barnun
is now free free for personal use and a
reasonable price for professional use
and I got nothing to do with these
people honestly I am not pedaling for
VMware VMware they it's just a great
product they make a fantastic product
VMware has made yet another but small
but Noble post merge the workstation Pro
Fusion Pro which is the Mac thing uh
desktop hypervisor projects are now
available for free for personal use that
means uh it's it's yeah virtual box was
never really a thing the cloud and
virtualization Biz now a broadcom
subsidiary has announced that its Pro
apps will be available through free and
Commercial
subscriptions so this is actually
something that's we're talking about
because when I had when I was paying for
workstation Pro every time they' have a
new version i' get this big h huge bill
that I had to pay to decide whether to
upgrade kind of like in the old days
when you used to do Adobe Photoshop and
you'd pay for the big thing and then
they went to a subscription model and
that's where all the money is and that's
what they've done the subscription model
works the best for most people because
you don't have to be you don't need it
all the time you just say I want it on
now and now I want it off on off on off
like a streaming service like zift like
your favorite game it's great
subscription service is fine I I totally
totally applaud this decision by BMW to
do this and I will be
very very excited to be able to tell or
help people use and set up Linux desktop
Linux in a server you know whatever you
want even free
BSD inside of a VM using workstation Pro
the biggest takeaway for with regard to
the beginner boost is rather than tell
you to use a free player which only
allows you to have one instance running
and not take snapshots or anything
that's all in Pro which you can now do
for free which you couldn't before I
mean this is big news this is fantastic
news for people who want to learn and
Tinker because with workstation Pro you
can actually have a whole bunch of
little BMS and you can set up your own
internal subnet that's all happening
right on your computer on your host
Network machine could be Windows could
be Mac it doesn't matter you can set up
all these little things you can practice
all of your network configurations you
can practice if you want to you can
practice snipping the network for art
packets you can do all kinds of things
that you could not do before without
paying or paying period right you would
have had to pay now with workstation Pro
as much memory as your system will allow
you can cut it all up and D it all up
and do that not to mention the fact that
VMware also has shared GPU access which
is means you can actually run you know a
game or whatever and share the GPU
across the systems which you cannot do
with kbm at least not by default and let
people are like oh just use kbm for
everything no VMware still does better
because it is it has had the consumer
facing product uh I mean people give
VMware false credit for having invented
virtualization all the time because they
were the first really big consumer
facing product with with you know with
VMware back in God what was it 90
something and now it's free you get it
for free so I'm super
excited um and uh yep it's a is it free
software as in yeah no and virtual box
is not free as in Libra either so
hopefully that'll make your day I'm sure
you've heard about it by now but I just
wanted to comment on it